teacherease.com 2016-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Common Goal Systems, Inc

Common Goal Systems takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

#### What this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers Common Goal Systems' treatment of personally identifiable information that Common Goal Systems collects when you are on the Common Goal Systems site, and when you use Common Goal Systems' services. This policy also covers Common Goal Systems' treatment of any personally identifiable information that Common Goal Systems' business partners share with Common Goal Systems or that Common Goal Systems may collect on a partner's site. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Common Goal Systems does not own or control, or to people that Common Goal Systems does not employ or manage.

#### Information Collection and Use

Common Goal Systems collects personally identifiable information when you are entered into the system by your local school. When using a Common Goal Systems site, you are not anonymous to us. Common Goal Systems automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, and the page you requested. Common Goal Systems uses information to understand our customer's usage of the web-site for the purpose of improving the end-user experience on the site.

#### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Common Goal Systems will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone. Common Goal Systems may send personally identifiable information about you to other companies or people when: We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Common Goal Systems to provide a product or service to you. (Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us.); We respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; or We find that your actions on our web sites violate the Common Goal Systems Terms of Service or any of our usage guidelines for specific products or services.

Common Goal Systems gives you the ability to edit your Common Goal Systems Account Information and preferences at any time.

#### Data Collected from Children

The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) applies to the online collection of personal information from children under 13. While Common Goal Systems holds personal information about children under 13, it does not explicitly or intentionally collect personal information from children under 13. There are no online forms within the system that request personal information from children under 13. Student personal information is entered into the system by school employees or parents. 

While Common Goal Systems does not explicitly or intentionally collect personal information from children under 13, it is possible for children under 13 to inadvertently enter personal information into the system. There are situations where children under age 13 can enter arbitrary data into the system (such as sending an email to a teacher or performing online classroom work), and in these cases the child could enter protected personal information.

This situation is covered in Common Goal Systems Terms of Service. The school, acting as the agent of the parents, consents to the collection children’s personal information for educational purposes. For more information, see: [https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/business-blog/2015/01/testing-testing-review-session-coppa-schools ](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/business-blog/2015/01/testing-testing-review-session-coppa-schools), <https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/complying-coppa-frequently-asked-questions#Schools>

Common Goal Systems will not use this information for commercial purposes or disclose it to unauthorized individuals. This information will be shared with school employees. The information will also be shared with individuals who have been granted access by school employees (typically parents or guardians). In certain situations, teachers can direct Common Goal Systems to make this information available to other members of the classroom community as part of the learning process.

A parent has the right to review their child’s personal information and may obtain the information by contacting the child’s school. The parent may ask Common Goal Systems to update or delete their child’s personal information through a request to their child’s school. 

A parent may request the termination of their child’s account through a request to their child’s school. Common Goal Systems, at the request of the school, will delete the child’s account and any personal information collected from the student. Any personal information will be deleted from our live data, but may remain in our backups. Common Goal Systems will have no liability whatsoever for any loss of data resulting from the termination of the child’s account and deletion of personal information.

#### Security

Your Common Goal Systems Account Information is password-protected for your privacy and security. In certain areas Common Goal Systems uses industry-standard SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Common Goal Systems may amend this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our pages.

#### Questions or Suggestions

If you have questions or suggestions please email us at support@common-goal.com, or contact us at:

Common Goal Systems, Inc.  
PO Box 392  
Lake Forest, IL 60045  
630-592-4200
